The Last Charge of the Calcutta Light Horse
The Sea Wolves is a war, action, thriller film directed by Andrew V. McLaglen.
A German spy is passing on information about the location of Allied ships in
the neutral harbor of Goa, India, with catastrophic results.
Unable to undertake a full military operation in the Portuguese stronghold, English intelligence brings out of
retirement a crew of geriatric ex-soldiers, veterans from World War I, using their age as cover.
These old soldiers are asked to take to the seas and
pull off an unlikely undercover mission.
Col. Lewis Pugh, played by Gregory Peck.
Capt. Gavin Stewart, played by Roger Moore.
Col. W.H. Grice, played by David Niven.
Jack Cartwright, played by Trevor Howard.
Mrs. Cromwell, played by Barbara Kellerman.
Major 'Yogi' Crossley, played by Patrick Macnee.
The Sea Wolves is a 1980 war film starring Gregory
Peck, Roger Moore and David Niven.
The film, which is based on the 1978 book Boarding Party by James Leasor, is
the true story of Operation Creek during the Second World War.
In the covert mission, the Calcutta Light Horse, part of the Cavalry Reserve in the British Indian Army, successfully sank
a German merchant ship in Mormugão Harbour in neutral Portugal's territory of Goa, India, on 9 March 1943.
The ship had a secret radio which was transmitting information about
Allied shipping to U-boats operating in the Indian Ocean.
The film, which starred veteran American and British actors, was
produced by Euan Lloyd and directed by Andrew V.
McLaglen; both had previously worked together on the
successful 1978 British-Swiss war film The Wild Geese.
The film explores themes of sea, ambush, world war
ii, based on true story, battle.
The tone is intense.